<notes>
  <note number="1">
    - Hi, I'm Jake

    - Work at ERC, projects varying from program evaluation,
      forecasting with childhood measures, and some modelling
      of dynamic discrete choice models

        - Actively develop my own software tools for these
          projects in Python. 

        - Aid in some parts of development
          in grmToolbox and the sructToolbox

        - In all projects, use Git for version control
          (and much more)

    - Today, present on version control in Economic Research

    - Boring and waste of time to explore syntax of version control

    - Hope to show:
        - How you already use version control
        - But maybe you do it poorly
        - Advantages of formal systems of version control
        - Give concepts, speed-up understanding
            - illustrate with conceptual examples
            - additional resources
  </note>
  <note number="2">
    - We all have versions of our work

    - Look on your computer and you will see...
  </note>
  <note number="3">
    - Which brings us to our topic...
  </note>
  <note number="4">
    - Historically, what was version control?

    - Poor methods lead to regional heterogeneity

    - But these methods (though digitized) persist today...

    - But there are better methods for those willing to 
      invest a bit of time (trust me, its worth it!)

    - There are some aspects central to all of these
      (next slide)
  </note>
  <note number="5">
    Infrastructure
    --------------

    - Remote file system
    - Local file system

    - Some method of comparing and sending files across
      these two systems, with the purpose of storing
      information about different versions

    - See examples

    - In local VCS, the remote and local are one in the same

    - In centralized, the central (remote) stores everything
      and is the central communicator for all actions

    - In distributional, both the remote and local file systems
      can function in the same way (they are copies!)
  </note>
  <note number="6,7">
    - usually speed advantages (no networking)

    - insured against loss (server is down, erased, etc.)
  </note>
  <note number="8">
    - Ok, this looks nice, but what advantages does it have
      for an Economic Researcher?

    - How will it enhance my workflow?

    - Arguably, these 3 concepts are central to your research

        - Having more efficient way to handle these aspects of
          research will free up time for...

            - creativity

            - focus on economic problems
    - And, Version Control lies at the center of these
      (hopefully not just because I created a Venn Diagram
      saying so)

    - I'll address each one of these topics throughout and
      show how formal systems of version control do much more
      than just manage version history.
  </note>
  <note number="9">
    1. The very nature of DVCS systems makes it easy to send
       around your project.

    2. Many tools developed to visualize projects, especially
       computer code and text (Github, Redmine, Ipython Notebook)

    3. Integration with existing knowledge and the creation of 
       new knowledge is faster!

    4. Scientific work can be quickly reviewed by peers or
       third parties

    5. See, for example, the grmToolbox online!
  </note>
  <note number="10">
    - Remember the Bible scribes? They wrote in the margins of the 
      book to keep track of version issues. 

    - Likewise, you've probably had to deal with plenty of ad-hoc
      methods of tracking history (README files or word-of-mouth)

    - You've been hesitant to try new methods, because the one
      you currently have "works" (non-linear work-flows)

        - Model Averaging, MCMC sampling

    - Only gets messier when you collaborate
  </note>
  <note number="11">
    - You might say, but I have no problems, my code
      doesn't need version history and I don't collaborate
      and I have no need for such an intricate vehicle of
      dissemenation and visibility. 

          - Raising issues, merge conflicts, these are problems
            I don't want to deal with--but you might already 
            do this (emailing versions) but you hardly notice it

    - You might be right. You're project might not require
      version control.

    - I hope to give you a quick guide to help you determine
      the benefit for yourself

    - And because I think Git is a good choice, I'll go over 
      important concepts to (hopefully) make learning Git a 
      bit easier
  </note>
  <note number="12">
    - Overview:

        - What is Git and how does it relate to my file system?

        - How do I "do" Git? (hint: the commands)

        - What is going on in there!??

        - Go back and help you understand those concepts after you've
          had time to see some basic functionality
  </note>
  <note number="14">
    - Begin with familiar setting (e.g. Github, or Athens)

    - This is all Git is

    - Everything stored in .git/ directory

        - Gitland vs. working directory
  </note>
  <note number="16">
    - Notice how I'm highlight that the file has changed, but that nothing
      in what I call "Gitland" has changed. Meaning, Git is not recording
      the change.
  </note>
  <note number="17">
    - When Pam is at a milestone, or maybe its the end of her workday, she 
      want to record her changes to Git. This means "committing" her work.
      This is the first Git concept I'll introduce. 
  </note>
  <note number="18">
    - Notice how "Gitland" has changed. I highlighted the Git 
      directory to show that Git has recorded a new snapshot to
      the commit history.
  </note>
  <note number="22">
    - Okay, let's take a step back and look at what we have done

    - We've actually explored a lot of the core functions of Git
  </note>
  <note number="23">
    - But how to make Git track a file?
  </note>
  <note number="25">
    - Let's make a new file

    - In white (not red, as before) because Git does not know this
      file, but it recognizes it as untracked

    - mention the .gitignore file
  </note>
  <note number="26">
    - Not anything new

    - We can commit these changes as before
  </note>
  <note number="28">
    - You have the core functionality now.
    
    - And there is value in just keeping track of your history
      in an efficient and organized way

    - But the benefits go way beyond. Git makes collaborating
      more effective.
  </note>
  <note number="29">
    - Typical mode of communication is through the remote
      central server. Though direct communication is possible.

    - Additional tools for communicating bugs. Github issue
      tracker
  </note>
  <note number="31">
    - What happened in that merge?

    - Need to introduce branching to understanding merging
  </note>
  <note number="33">
    - For the economist, this means adding unobservable agent heterogeneity
      to the model (as in the grmToolbox)

    - For the statistician/econometrician, this means adding a new sampler
      for a Markov Chain (as in ModelAveraging)

    - Experimentation without worry

    - Checkout Numpy or Statsmodels on github to see this workflow in action
  </note>
  <note number="35">
    - By location, I mean the state of your files, literally what the files look like, 
      over the course of development.
  </note>
  <note number="37">
    - Stuck in the mud if you have made modifications to files

    - Head must point to a branch
  </note>
  <note number="38">
    - Won't go into details

    - Merging works on BRANCHES, it is the counterpart to a simultaneous
      workflow.

    - Allows to bring successful "experiments" into your core analysis

    - EXAMPLE: After MCMC sampling worked, I merged my sampler branch with
      my master branch
  </note>
  <note number="42">
    - You are in Git limbo when resolving a merge conflict

    - There is no automatic way to do this

    - But Git makes it EXPLICIT and APPARENT when there are conflicts
        - easier to spot
        - easier to fix
  </note>
  <note number="44">
    - This is special commit, a merge commit

    - Has two parents!
  </note>
  <note number="47">
    - Familiar with the concepts

    - Tie it together
  </note>
  <note number="48">
    - Form a mental partition of Gitland and working directory

    - Framework for understanding the commands
  </note>
</notes>